wopg.org 2016-10-20

# WOPG Privacy and Cookies Policy - Words of Peace

This website is administered by Foundation Words of Peace Global (WOPG), with domicile at Kabelweg 37, 1014 BA Amsterdam, The Netherlands, and registered in the Amsterdam Trade Registry under number 34312991.

_By accepting this Privacy Policy, you agree to your data being processed by WOPG as described herein._

Words of Peace Global is an independent charitable foundation set up by individuals inspired by Prem Rawat’s message of peace. Funded by donations, Words of Peace Global provides access to materials and financial support for Prem Rawat’s work, including his public events around the world, where needed.

We are strongly committed to protecting your privacy online and have taken the necessary steps to safeguard the information you share with us.

Listed below is information about what data is collected, how it is treated, and how you can contact us with questions or concerns regarding your privacy.

##### **What data we collect**

When you visit our website, you may choose to provide us with your personal details – whether you send a question to our help desk, inquire about the Keys, or sign up on our mailing list, for example; you choose which data you want to give us. For each specific purpose, if requested by you, we will let you know how we use these collected data, and remove those data, should you ask us to.

In addition, when you make a contribution to WOPG through this website, we ask you for your credit card information. Please note that credit card details are held securely by our payment provider Worldpay and only used by them to process your contribution.

We adhere to European data protection principles.

##### **How we safeguard your privacy**

We use secure technology to safeguard your information and the content on this website. Such information is protected with state-of- the-art firewalls, including stateful packet inspection. We also routinely perform proactive monitoring and intrusion detection and implement denial of service attack mitigation processes. We use a Unix-hardened operating system for our servers, which are maintained by certified security staff.

When we use a third party for processing part of our data, we choose a party that provides sufficient guarantees in respect to security measures needed for processing personal data.

##### **How we use the collected data**

We use the collected personal data in order to provide you with the services or content requested by you and to perform activities related to such services and products, including processing your contributions. We do not store personal data any longer than is needed.

We will not disclose your personal information to third parties without your consent, except when this is necessary in the interests of: 

  * a. State security.
  * b. The prevention, detection and prosecution of criminal offences.
  * c. Important economic and financial interests of the State and other public entities;
  * d. Supervising compliance with legal provisions established in the interests referred to under (b) and (c), or
  * e. Protecting the data subject or the rights and freedoms of other persons.

##### **Cookies**

A “cookie” is a small piece of data that is sent to your browser and is stored on your device. Cookies are used to collect information about the user such as web surfing behavior or user preferences for a specific website to improve website services and content.

We use 4 cookies to improve the website’s usability, analyze the use of the website, administer the website, prevent fraud, improve the security of the website, and personalize the website for each user based on their language preferences.

All of these cookies do not store personal data.

We use Google Analytics cookies, for which we have data sharing disabled and in combination with which we do not use other Google Analytics services. We have a data processing agreement, and we protect your personal privacy by masking the last octet of your IP address.

Cookies may be deactivated through your internet browser’s settings preferences.

##### **International**

We are a global organization with people from all over the world in different parts of the organization. That means that personal data of someone might be visible in countries that do not adhere to specific privacy regulations.

However, as an organization, we respect privacy regulations, and our protocol includes having an agreement from every person in WOPG, employee or volunteer, with access to personal data to respect and protect personal data and to work accordingly.

##### **Information about your rights**

You have the right to access, correct, supplement, delete, or block your personal data by contacting us via our helpdesk, via phone at +00 31 20 416 2050, or via postal mail at **Foundation Words of Peace Global, P.O. Box 20627, 1001 NP Amsterdam.  
**

All data processing by WOPG is in compliance with the applicable Dutch Personal Data Act and European Directives. To ensure such compliance, WOPG may periodically revise this Privacy Policy.
